okay yo yo yo let's get back to this
we're back okay so that was a call very
excitingly from get around we're going
to racetrack tomorrow and I wanted to
drive down in a Tesla with the new
autopilot so I have some bad news about
that route you posted it's still too new
so this one's too new for a different
reason
see that pulled data but still can't get
Sat position something is wrong so
what's happening is we're downloading
from NASA's servers all of the ephemeris
data um the problem is NASA hasn't
updated for that so does anybody have a
grape and or out from like yesterday if
there's no sound what you can't hear me
oh there is okay good you can hear me
right it's working good huh yeah you got
that now you all got sound you broke
your alright so we need an older
rekt gotta go older gotta go older than
that one who wants to volunteer an older
route I think one day we can do but this
is still from today though I don't know
I don't understand this pulled data but
still can't get sad position let's take
a look at the code and get that info
this is all gonna be open sourced if L
if self auto update
yeah it has to be a great panda with an
antenna now you don't need to great
pandas one great pandas good okay
pulled data but still can't get Sat
position something is wrong
Harold why doesn't this work pedestrians
are mapped to all right who wants to
volunteer a new route posted on slack
and I will use it you need to have a
gray panda and it needs to be more than
a day old yeah so the prom is that
didn't get the location of the SATs
right so here what happens when I try to
run it is look if it brings up the
mapping interface it downloads this
stuff but it can't download this no this
looks so solid because of your new maybe
I was showing off the thingy in one of
the deliveries yeah
no just just a gray kinda just a grape
and is good but no Harold's not here
leaves all around
yeah yeah
all right we're gonna stable get around
called no they're like I can't make any
guarantees they like took some
information down to make me feel
important really yeah right the scope is
like it alright so who wants to post a
route in the slack that they want to
volunteer yeah so just right now pulled
data but still can't get sat position
something is wrong okay oh we got we got
a newer one now I'm a blogger just like
my hero Logan Paul and PewDiePie
alright let's try this one oh no that
didn't work at all Oh see guys we still
have a lot of work to do on our mapping
I don't know what the problem with this
one is what's your dog like dig in you
gotta give me a dongle I think I can
look it up in secret user admin tool but
I don't know why that one didn't work
that one just screamed at me oh that
might have been during the great
database
no it's Python exceptions the mappers
really flaky right now we're gonna make
it work though we're gonna get it to
work on one route so Larry I need your
dog lighting
don't have a good way to search for okay
I'm gonna let's let's move the scope
he's over here oh oh sweet we got it
okay we got it done waiting alright
let's type that in here and then let's
try like minute 12 it's driving it fly
oh come on work work work work work oh
oh oh this is exciting okay it's running
log oh that's way long ago now I don't
know if way long ago it's gonna work but
okay all right it's cashing your frames
this is exciting it's gotta run a few
logs let's go let's go let's go it's
very exciting I know back but you guys
when it starts making Maps it gets super
exciting I will move the mapper over to
this screen here yeah so it's waiting
for images now so it's got to finish
processing the logs now the one that
might fail is called mesh three geez
okay so this is mesh 3d now okay we're
downloading all the data from NASA
oh yeah download data from NASA come on
data from NASA now basically if your
route makes it through all of this that
means it's a Goldstar minute okay all
right we're downloading from NASA this
is pretty exciting a little slow today
this mapping is brought to you by pure
leave unsweetened black tea the purest
why do we need a femoris data so we know
okay so now it's trying to get a fix
let's see if it can get a fix oh it
hasn't gotten a fix for a while now this
is another bug we need to fix up but
this is the closest we've been so far
come on get a fix see it's trying to
initialize
no you won't be on sizing the mapping
pipeline we will be open sourcing the
localization cut down oh yeah you got a
map backwards you guys don't know the
trick you got a drive back with you liar
drives backwards he knows that map ok
but it's not actually mapping yet let's
try a different one
let's try the previous minute but this
route to the furthest we've gotten so
far ok mine's downloading the ship from
NASA not everything always downloads
from NASA only the ones that fail it
prints now he's not yeah changed it why
backwards for mapping ah basically it's
very easy to get the depth of things
that are close and not the things that
are far away um you know you can also
use a camera pointing backwards works
pretty well
yeah ok so it's running mesh 3d I hope
feeling up there's just a lot of bugs
and mystery dirt that's why things not
working ok so if you see here the red is
what the gray pandas saying and the blue
is what the cameras saying and this is
of course in full 3d oh yeah you see the
traffic light some of that oh good no
that's really good yeah yes you see
those traffic lights there hey cars
ponder those traffic lights there yo ok
guys one mapping yo I'm telling you
every mapping company you're gonna cry
when they see how good this is how many
map point per feet I mean you can look
at all the map points we're really not
skimping on the data here ok so it looks
like we just kind of spent a lot of time
chillin at this light
we're gonna sit in virtual trip we spend
a lot of time in comas sitting in
virtual traffic I know right those
traffic lights are maps like now we know
exactly where in the world they are see
you know the ones back there the ones
over here I know we do sparse mats not
dense mats you can't promise the scope
is too much you like you like you know I
wrote the mapping the the next thing I'm
about to show you when we look at the
maps oh they love the mapping this stuff
is accurate to 10 centimeters and each
one of these points like okay well
there's a tiny disparity there will come
a V the V block can be open sourced okay
so we'll give it a little bit more time
um Larry coming through with the map
this is a user Rhett this isn't even my
round we do get your pictures in color
but the maps are only made in black and
white right now
[Music]
that's kind of true that's why we spend
more compressive this on it alright so
this is like a real 3d map and then what
we're gonna see assuming the next step
works is we're gonna insert all of these
points yeah this is for self-driving
this is so we can know exactly where
every car in the world goes and by
knowing that we can we can train models
better we can offer things like traffic
lights and stop signs and all you need
to make all this possible
but all you need to make all this
possible is an eon and a gray panda how
do you map trees too we do map trees
though we do also know that they're
trees we run a sag net sometimes but the
second up takes even longer so if you
thought this mapping was slow we're
gonna run this of course on a million
machines in Azure how we're features
selected from a city in Oregon how our
features selected yeah well then you
don't need to rely on land Marcus
mappings pretty good see like we know
exactly where that car traveled right so
it's really cool is um Larry I don't
know if you drove if you drove through
there on another day but if you drove
through the same place we can try to
even localize the two with respect to
each other this is a derivative of an
open-source program called orb slam
we're using some parts of it using an
optimizer called g2o I started for the
charge cable of you you do have a charge
cable don't worry it's not fighting any
features on that have we used up as
you're free credits now we still have
more but yeah we're making maps so you
see we're hacking the poses in a running
pose optimization to make sure that's
all good we're computing the cameras
calibration at every stat do we map
lanes yeah you see what mapping lanes
right now you see all the features on
the links um so we know that they are we
know that they're lanes from our from
our segmentation network okay so now I
was writing the map to the desk and then
it's gonna put the map in the database
oh and then we can figure out where that
was
what if there's a roadblock the maps are
cool we like the maps global maps yeah
oh no we're not gonna start using
thousands of us okay cool
so that's done alright so now we're
inserting the map into the database cool
okay so we have the origin here so let's
go in here
I don't oppose slack I'm close to where
we mean Twitter you never knew Twitter I
can copy/paste the origin of the map
here so we can know kind of where we're
gonna have to lock right right over here
here's the start of the router ah so
where are we oh we are up an organ or up
an organ all right cool all right
between Eugene and Portland sounds good
umm so we're gonna insert keyframes now
we're inserting all those points into
the map now this is of course gonna run
a massive scale this is me just testing
in a one computer we're gonna run this
automatically as part of our pipeline
and all your routes come in and they're
gonna contribute to the map alright
let's go to the map now
it might totally be wrong this is very
beta stuff all right there we go we got
some points up there up in Oregon let's
zoom in zoom in oh yeah this is the
greenness where the car went it loads
everything in yeah so basically your car
is gonna live stream load this all in oh
no oh no I clicked oh no a mouse slip a
mouse slip you guys a mouse slip okay
we're going back
I hate we're on our way to Oregon it's
gonna take a little bit to get there oh
wow we got a lot of scope ease up oh ok
let's refresh this let's go
okay so we have a bunch of different
maps down here like we can track we
check dis engagements on this map we'll
just go down here to orb slam alright so
we'll go up here back to Oregon oh yeah
here we go and here is that segment that
we just mapped I won't slip with the
mouse this time I'll be very precise
with my movements yeah and that's full
three dimensions so you can see how well
the lane markings line up with the road
pretty well so these these are the trees
you should give these all color we can
go down here we're building a full 3d
map so you see that these maps are
actually accurate to which lane you're
in umm they're more accurate than the
other than the satellite imagery
we're gonna see if you zoom up see those
are the maps of the trees what does the
point fix up I don't know what that does
but those people just showed up let's
try mapping another one of those
segments it's got to run a few frame
gashes but yeah so that's what our our
complete maps of the world are gonna
look like we're gonna go a lot further
with this we're gonna offer we're gonna
add color we just got this working
tonight guys this will be available to
everybody
this is the kind of stuff we're gonna
we're gonna open source I mean then
we're gonna provide an API for people to
localize within the map and you know
it's just there's just so much stuff
that's possible with this technology
yeah yeah so everybody who has a gray
panda and an eon will be mapped and yeah
I mean that's what the Goldstar minute
program is for so if we go over here to
our medium we can look at the Goldstar
minute every route that Matt matches
these requirements here we go look we're
mapping another segment here
why gray panda because we have to know
not just where you are locally but where
you are globally here we are making
another math we live one camera so your
subjective things like scaled if no
great neighbors have gotten stock they
will be in stock at the end of the month
but um yeah look at all those points on
that house that's gonna be a nice map
all right guys
mail a gigantic big gold star maybe we
will mail I took big gold star whoever
gets the most you have to be updated to
four point three as well so gray panda
beyond open pilot four point three four
point three one check it out it's in
devel
how many gray at the end of the month
we're getting 250 and then we're gonna
get another thousand at the end of next
month
so there's gonna be tons and tons of
great pant is available for you people
to buy alright guys I'm gonna show you
something else kind of cool I'm gonna
show you something else that just that
just blows my mind um we're gonna head
downstairs
come on Wi-Fi here's my Amazon review of
a panda I gave it three stars we need to
work to make it five stars
what does Eddie been up to oh we don't
talk about Eddie's up to but we will
talk about this guy's
welcome to Akane I stopped have you ever
seen
ar e on Z yawn yawns yawns yawns yawns
yawns these things are moving man we're
moving weight yawns are just shipping
shipping shipping we got a bunch of
midnight blacks over here
I'm just 10 yawns in each one of these
boxes so we literally have hundreds of
yawns yawns for days sorry if it's
frozen but my investors happy you'll
have to ask them
I don't whoops all right guys I'll come
out of closet
come on frozen we see our testing closet
sure you guys seen her testing closet
cool yeah I'm out of the closet yeah
sweet you guys know the
3d printer lands here we are in 3d
printer land
out that room yeah well out of that room
San Francisco 3d printer land so smooth
love this thing show you guys the GPU
form I will show the GPU farm few farms
over here
you know I'm me really on those
computers down there
where's Fillmore let's see where
film-wise get cam we got Gio we got
pistachio no is feel more broken up this
film are more right there yeah the
coarser cases are pretty nice right
alright guys thanks for joining
that was mapping this periscope make
sure all for and updates yeah no and I
have to Ford up its yet yeah guys check
out you know always a calm down AI slash
shop buy stuff buy merch guys if you
think the map is good now like we just
got that working tonight
we're gonna continue to work on that
we're hiring we're hiring um we came
into some money recently so we are we
are hiring if you're good or you know
anyone who's good we're hiring for
people for the maps no we're hiring like
a serious team and I'm gonna give it all
away we're gonna give it all away we're
gonna give it all away because maps
should be free so if you work at a
mapping company or Adelaide our company
I'll be afraid because kawaii is coming
for you get your yawns get your great
pandas help out in the greatest open
sourcing mapping effort in history
you thought ways was good this is ways
2.0 this is uh this is way better how
higher thanks guys